http://www.bhncdsb.ca/news/freedom-information-privacy-and-access

Freedom of Information, Privacy and Access | Brant Haldimand Norfolk Catholic District School Board
Skip to main content
...
edit-jump--2Staff LinksCommunity Use of SchoolsBrightspace/D2LBHN Hub Outlook MailProcurement Services
Search form
Find Us On...
Student Trustee
Questions or concerns?
Before and After School Childcare
Canada's Anti-Spam Legislation (CASL)
MedicAlert for Students
Questions or concerns?
Registration - Elementary (K-8)
Home Instruction
School Within A College (SWAC)
Parent Resources
Specialist High Skills Major (SHSM)
View the policy
How do I apply?
How much does it cost?
My School Locator
Registration - Elementary (K-8)
Transcripts
You are hereHome»BOARD»Freedom of Information, Privacy and Access
Freedom of Information, Privacy and Access
The following information is provided to promote understanding and awareness of the Brant Haldimand Norfolk Catholic District School Board’s access and privacy practices in accordance with the Education Act, Municipal Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act (MFIPPA) and the Personal Health Information Privacy Act (PHIPA).
Municipal Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act (MFIPPA)
The Municipal Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act is a provincial law that requires the protection of personal information and provides individuals with a right of access to government records subject to specific and limited exemptions. Included in the Act are specific provisions for how your personal information may be collected, used, retained, disclosed and disposed of.
How does the Board collect and use personal information?
Personal information is collected directly from parents, guardians or students under the authority of the Education Act and is used to plan and deliver educational programs and services which best meet student needs. Personal information is collected indirectly only with the consent of parents, guardians or students.
Under the Education Act, the Principal is required to compile a pupil record known as the Ontario Student Record (OSR). This record tracks a student’s academic progress through the Ontario Education system and follows students when they change schools. Access and use of this record is regulated by the Ontario Student Record (OSR) Guideline 2000 available on the Ministry of Education’s website.
How does MFIPPA provide a right of access to records?
The Municipal Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act contains access and privacy protection provisions. This means that individuals have a right to request access to general records and their own personal information held by the Board in accordance with the MFIPPA and the Education Act. Exemptions to the right of access are limited and specific and are defined in the MFIPPA.
How do I access my personal information?
Students/parents/guardians can request access to information held by the Board by contacting the teacher or principal of the school they or their child attends. Please be aware that while an individual has access to their own personal information and general records, they do not have a right to access personal information about another individual. Board staff must comply with the Municipal Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act and the Education Act and will provide you with the information you request only if you are legally entitled to receive it.
How do I access general information?
General information about our programs and services and contact information is posted on the Board website. For access to more specific information, you may contact the respective department or program area.  If the information is not readily available they may direct you to make a formal Freedom of Information request. A formal access request will be processed in accordance with the requirements of the MFIPPA.
Individuals may also make a more specific or formal access request under the Municipal Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act.
How do I make a formal Freedom of Information (FOI) request?
You may make a request by completing a Freedom of Information Request form. Completed forms must include a $5.00 application fee paid by cash or cheque payable to the Brant Haldimand Norfolk Catholic District School Board. Provide as much detail as possible about the information you are requesting.
Requests can be sent to the attention of: Manager of Communications and Community Relations (Privacy and Information Management Officer), PO Box 217, 322 Fairview Drive, Brantford, ON N3T 5M8
Questions or Concerns?
If you have any questions or concerns related to the access to information or the protection of personal privacy please contact the Manager of Communications (Privacy and Information Management Officer) at 519-756-6505 Ext. 234.
Quick tabs
Brightspace/D2L
Register Now
Schools
Transportation
Board Information
Brant Haldimand Norfolk
Catholic District School Board
322 Fairview Drive,
P.O. Box 217,
Website Questions?
Email: webmaster@bhncdsb.ca
